<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mulpat | Nathen Harvey]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.nathenharvey.com/blog/categories/mulpat/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.nathenharvey.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-06T21:21:37-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.nathenharvey.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nathen Harvey]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nathen@nathenharvey.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Chef - Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.nathenharvey.com/blog/2012/12/06/learning-chef-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-06T17:07:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.nathenharvey.com/blog/2012/12/06/learning-chef-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In November of 2012, <a href="https://twitter.com/mulpat">Patrick Mulder</a> posted a <a href="http://lists.opscode.com/sympa/arc/chef/2012-11/msg00389.html">request on the Chef mailing list</a>.  He was</p>

<p><blockquote><p>looking for some 1-1 teaching via skype to help me get going in setting up a basic DB server from scratch, as well as a basic dev server as intermediary step.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I thought this would be an excellent opportunity to feed my recent addiction to Google+ Hangouts.  I would provide Patrick some one-on-one tutoring if he would agree to having the sessions <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l7-nAHdplD4&amp;list=PLKK5zTDXqzFM53J6-rikDrqbbY0Pu-9SP">broadcast live on YouTube</a>.  We had some technical issues getting our first session going in a Google+ Hangout but we were able to meet via Skype and I captured video of the session.</p>

<p>Our goal is to help you get up and running on Chef by following our progress.  The intent is to have additional sessions run via Google+ Hangouts that are steamed live to YouTube.  This post includes our first session which has been broken into nine short videos.  I hope you enjoy these videos and are able to learn something about Chef, too.  Both Patrick and I are looking forward to your feedback on this experiment.</p>

<p>You can <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l7-nAHdplD4&amp;list=PLKK5zTDXqzFM53J6-rikDrqbbY0Pu-9SP">watch all of the videos in the YouTube playlist</a> or keep reading and watch each video in turn.</p>

<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>In this video we introduce ourselves and the project.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/l7-nAHdplD4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h2>Overview of Chef</h2>

<p>In this video we visit the newly launched <a href="http://docs.opscode.com">Chef Documentation Site</a> and look over the <a href="http://docs.opscode.com/chef_overview.html">Overview of Chef</a> diagram.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/2BCNpHNZzy8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>For our project the Chef Workstation will be Patrick's laptop, the Chef Server will be <a href="http://www.opscode.com/hosted-chef/">Opscode Hosted Chef</a>, and the first node we create will be a virtual machine that is managed by <a href="http://vagrantup.com">Vagrant</a>.</p>

<h2>Register for Hosted Chef</h2>

<p>In this video Patrick will <a href="http://www.opscode.com/hosted-chef/">sign-up for a Hosted Chef account</a>. We will use the free trial which allows you to manage up to 5 nodes for free.  After signing-up and verifying his email address, Patrick will <a href="https://manage.opscode.com">login to Hosted Chef</a> at <a href="https://manage.opscode.com">https://manage.opscode.com</a>.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/7n_mwo9-pIA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
